A Guide to the Patrick H. Butler Collection, 1911-1990
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Patrick H. Butler Collection, 1911-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Butler, Patrick H., Jr., 1908-1992
Ms2019-015
1.2 Cubic Feet 3 boxes
The Patrick H. Butler Collection includes materials from 1911-1990. The collection contains personal papers and photographs relating to Butler's tenure as a Virginia Tech student and his alumni relationship with the university.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Patrick H. Butler Collection was donated to Special Collections in three acrruals in July 2017, August 2017, and November 2018.
Biographical Note
Patrick H. Butler, Jr. was born on January 20, 1908 in Nottoway County, VA. Before attending Virginia Tech, Patrick attended Jackson School in Petersburg, VA. Patrick attended Virginia Tech, then known as Virginia Polytechnic Institute (V.P.I.) from 1926-1930. While at Virginia Tech, Patrick was a member of the Petersburg Club, the Highty-Tighties, the Chemical Club, and the Glee Club. In his Junior year, Patrick served as a Sergeant in the Band.
Butler married Rebecca Anne Johnson of Ripley, Ohio in June of 1932. In 1935, Butler and his wife lived in Anderson, Madison, Indiana. They moved to Alexandria, VA sometime between 1935-1940. Patrick worked as an executive assistant at Alexandria Gas Co. Anne worked as a stenographer in real estate. Butler registered for the draft in 1940. Patrick H. Butler died on December 25, 1992.
Scope and Content
The Patrick H. Butler Collection includes materials from 1911-1990. The collection contains personal papers and photographs relating to Butler's tenure as a Virginia Tech student and his alumni relationship with the university. The collection consists of two series: Personal Materials and Images.
Arrangement Note
The Patrick H. Butler Collection is arranged in two series: Personal Materials and Images.
I. Personal Materials contains two sub-series: Materials from Tenure as a Student and Alumni Materials. Materials from Tenure as a Student contains the following items: Graduation Commencement Bulletins, ROTC Dinner Menu, and Thanksgiving Dinner Menus. Alumni Materials contains materials relating to the Class of 1930 35th, 40th, 45th, 50th, and 55th Reunions, the Corps of Cadets, the Highty-Tighties, Paid Student Loans, Tech Triumph Scores, the Washington Chapter - V.P.I. Alumni Association, the William E. Lavery Inauguration, and the World War II Memorial. Personal Materials also contains materials from correspondence, public schools of Petersburg, German Dance Cards, V.P.I. Memorabilia, V.P.I. Stickers, V.P.I. Publications, and a V.P.I. Scrapbook. This series is arranged alphabectically by subject.
II. Images contains photographs and a postcard. The photographs are of different V.P.I. scenes, honeymoon photos, and a postcard showing the V.P.I. bookstore's offerings. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Rights Statements for Archival Description
The guide to the Patrick H. Butler Collection by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Alumni publication; Highty Tighties; Thanksgiving; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute--Corps of Cadets; Virginia Polytechnic Institute. Alumni Association
Contents List
- Series I: Personal Materials, 1911-1990
  - Alumni Materials
    - Class of 1930 35th, 40th, and 45th Reunions, 1965-06-03-1975-10-18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Class of 1930 50th and 55th Reunions, 1980-10-10-1985-04-13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Corps of Cadets, 1953-03-01-1990-03-27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Highty-Tighties, 1962-11-15-1966-03-31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Paid Student Loans, 1930-03-21-1935-08-21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Tech Triumph Scores, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Washington Chapter - V.P.I. Alumni Association, 1962-09-11-1965-09-10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - William H. Lavery Inauguration, 1975-10-16-1975-10-17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - World War II Memorial Materials (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1911-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - German Dance Cards, 1927-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Materials from Public Schools of Petersburg, 1916-11-13-1917-06-11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Materials from Tenure as Student, 1926-1930
    - Graduation/Commencement Bulletins, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ROTC Dinner Menu, 1929-07-23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Thanksgiving Dinner Menus, 1926-11-28, 1927-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - V.P.I. Memorabilia (Box 3)
  - V.P.I. Publications, 1929-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - V.P.I. Scrapbook (Box 2)
  - V.P.I. Stickers (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series II: Images, 1926-1966
  - Honeymoon, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Postcards (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Tech, 1926-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)